

About Me

I'm a driven and enthusiastic Software Engineer specialising in React and JavaScript. I have a keen eye for design and pride myself in creating pixel perfect, responsive web applications. I believe in creating interfaces that not only functionally work but are also a joy for the user to experience. I have worked in multiple engineering teams, varying in size, and am comfortable in Scrum and Waterfall teams.

Knowledge

Tech Stack React, Redux, JavaScript, Jest, HTML, CSS, React Native, Mongo, Node

Toolkit Visual Studio Code, Insomnia, Robo3T, SourceTree, Jira, Figma, Slack

Operating Systems Comfortable with all versions of Mac OS and Windows

Other Firebase, Google Tag Manager/ Analytics, WordPress, Craft CMS

Employment History

Concrete - Farringdon, London Software Engineer

July 2019 - Present

Concrete is, at its core, a task management system for the retail industry. However it has grown to include compliance, messaging and file management elements which connect brand HQs to the store workers.

I primarily work on the Front End application, however am also comfortable creating and modifying application endpoints.

- Tech lead on all engagement and resource components of the application
- Built a real-time messaging system using Firebase
- Built the phone application using React Native
- Mentored several junior and legacy staff members, retraining them to use React
- Build, refactor and write unit tests for components
- · Worked heavily with the design team to improve the reusability of our components and design patterns

Dauntless - Epsom, Surrey Lead Web/UI Developer

September 2015 - July 2019 (Promotion from Front End Web Developer, September 2017)

- Lead a team of developers to produce a broad range of digital applications and WordPress websites.
- Development of multiple UI component kits in React
- · Worked with and advised the design team on latest digital trends, and best practices
- Helped put together scope of works and proposals in order to help win work opportunities
- Met clients face-to-face for meetings and training purposes, including international clients
- · Carried out interviews to hire for our New York and Phoenix offices



Employment History (Continued)

Firedog - Old Street, London September 2013 - August 2015

Web and UI Developer

- Worked with a team of developers and designers to concept, produce and maintain custom WordPress themes, static web pages and email templates
- Production of iOS application using PhoneGap
- Optimization of page speed and SEO
- Training clients on how to use their website
- Designing interactive wireframes

JVC Professional - Staples Corner, London - Marketing Executive August 2012 - August 2013

Waitrose - Worcester Park, London - Fresh Foods Partner September 2009 - August 2012

Knibbs Associates - Reigate, Surrey - Web Designer (Work Experience) September 2009 - October 2009

Education

BSc (Hons) Business Computing Systems - City University London - 2:1 2011 - August 2015

Work Based Project	1:1 - 74% (Dissertation) "To develop a software solution to a real
--------------------	-------------------------	---------------------------------------------

clients problem"

Electronic Commerce 1:1 - 92% "To produce a website capable of allowing users to

purchase a product online"

Business Systems 1:1 - 76% "Understanding and creating systems to enhance the

success of a Business"

Programming in Java 1:1 - 70% "Developing our skills in the production of Java programs"

IT Security 2:1 - 65.8% "Learning the skills required to identify, prevent and to

preserve the integrity, availability and confidentiality of information

system resources"

Computation and Reasoning 2:1 - 62.8% "How to compute solutions, understanding the strengths

and limitations and how to model them"

Human Computer Interaction 2:1 - 62% "Study, planning and design of the interaction between

users and computers"

Networks and Operating Systems 2:1 - 62% "Understanding the major operating systems components

and system scheduling"



Education (Continued)

4 A Levels Glyn Technology School, Epsom

2009 - 2011

Double IT (B,C) Business Studies (B) History (B)

11 GCSEs Glyn Technology School, Epsom

2007 - 2009 5 As, 5 Bs, 1 C

Interests

Outside of work I like to keep active, I enjoy running, long walks and a round of golf whenever the weather permits. I also love to game, whether that's exploring new worlds, jumping into my racing simulator or getting competitive online with my friends. Additionally I like exploring, finding hidden eating spots in London, and travelling further afield and learning about different cultures.

To view my work please see my online portfolio at mattmuirhead.co.uk.

References available upon request.